Vinayak More

Senior Software Engineer

Passionate Software Engineer with 8+ years of Industry experience in developing distributed applications with Angular and Java Ecosystem. Well-versed with Agile methodologies of Software development lifecycle and Practical experience in product development & deployment in financial services and E-commerce industry.

☑ vinayak.more914@gmail.com

= +91 72084 67350

in linkedin.com/in/vm914

github.com/vinayak-more

CORE STRENGTHS

Java	JavaScript	Angular	React	Data Struc	ctures	Algorithm	s Desing P	atterns	Spring Boot	RESTful API
Google	Protobuff	Java Messag	ging Service	SQL	Shell S	Script M	licroservices	Maven	CI/CD Pipeli	ne Agile M

WORK EXPERIENCE

Morgan Stanley | ➡ Manager - Senior Software Engineer | ➡ April, 2022 - Present | ♥ Mumbai ➡ Java 8, Angular 14, Spring Boot, REST API, Hibernate, Mockito, MSSQL, Shell Scripts, Microservices, TeamCity

- Working as a **Full Stack** Engineer in an agile squad leading the team, owning responsibility of design, develop and deliver business requirements.
- Contributing in Frontend development in Angular and Java-Spring in backend to provide a end-to-end solution.
- Implemented caching mechanism to reduce External API calls by 10x to improve Rest API service reponse time.
- Used Data Structures and Problem solving methods to improve the performance of the existing system.
- Mentored junior members in the team and Participated in <u>Conducting interviews</u> for the firm.

JP Morgan Chase | ♣ Associate - Senior Software Engineer | ★ May,2019 - April, 2022 | ♠ Mumbai
♦ Java 8, React JS, Spring Boot, LMAX Disruptor, Google Protobuff, JDBC, Mockito, Sybase, TIBCO EMS, Microservices, Jenkins

- Worked as an Application Engineer resposible for design, developement, delivery and L3 support of the application used globally for processing millions of Market Orders.
- Implemented Web UI Live Reload for latest Market orders with *React, Web Sockets* and *Message brokers* for migrating existing Windows Application.
- Integrated LMAX Disruptor for processing high volume of Market Orders and Executed Trades.
- For microservice-to-microservice data exchange, used Google Protobuff to reduce network data transfer and increase consistency.
- Worked on Financial Information Exchange (<u>FIX</u>) Protocol for Market Exchange connectivity.
- Setup and configured CICD Pipeline using **Jenkins** 2.0 based (internal) tool.
- Mentored junior members in the team and Encouraged team to follow TDD.

Infibeam Avenues | ➡ Software Engineer | ➡ July, 2015 - May, 2019 | ♥ Mumbai ➡ Java 8, Angular 4, Spring Boot, REST API, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSF, Hibernate, Mockito, MySQL, Jenkins

- Worked as a Full Stack Engineer on Feature development and Technology Migration.
- Migrated existing Lagecy application from Google Web ToolKit(GWT) to Angular and Spring Boot Application
- Integrated third-party vendors for flights and hotels end to end booking flow.
- Implemented multi-threaded approach for reducing response time by **3x** in Flights and Hotels Searches.
- Worked on domain based microservices architecture interconnected by Rest APIs and Message Brokers.
- Created an Innovative solution for managing frequent static changes in websites by designing and developing an In-House <u>Content Management System</u> (CMS) for B2C websites.
- Contributed in Sprint planning and effort estimations.

EDUCATIONAL DETAILS